Guaynabo, Puerto Rico United States, 00969 **OMAR FLORES**

WEBSITE: OMARFQ.COM

(787) 910 - 4288 omarenriquefq@gmail.com

MISSION STATEMENT

Curiosity-driven Software Engineer with a serious love for learning new skills and technologies. I'm well versed in programming languages such as Python, JavaScript, and C#; currently learning Go. I've worked on projects that used Serverless and Client-Server architectures with a mix of patterns such as MVC, RESTful API, and Event-Driven Design. My interests and areas of focus include but are not limited to Distributed Systems, Backend Development, and Software Engineering in general. Adaptability, humility, and discipline are my core values that guide every single action and decision that I take.

EMPLOYMENT

Web Developer II INVID, LLC September 2021 - Present

- · Led the development and design of a REST API leveraging the use of Azure Functions and the Node.js SDK.
- Simplified the project's backend architecture by introducing Sequelize.js as the ORM of choice to handle all gueries sent to the Azure SQL Database as well as to perform simple CRUD operations.
- · Responsible for monitoring and setting up an Azure SQL Database instance on the client's tenant.
- Optimized average request duration from 1 second to <250ms.
- Currently developing an application with complex business requirements for the Oficina de Administración de Tribunales (OAT) using tools such as .NET 6 (MVC and Razor Pages), Entity Framework, and SQL Server.

Software Developer II

Wovenware, Inc

January 2021 - September 2021

- Led the development efforts of two (2) of the eight (8) most important deliverables of the project, namely two Interfaces that sat between our system and a Local Government Agency that made possible the exchange and validation of data between these two entities.
- Developed said Interfaces using mostly Microsoft Azure tools including Azure Logic Apps (ARM templates contained more than 6000 lines of JSON), App Services, Storage Accounts, Integration Service Environment (ISE), Virtual Machines, SQL Database, Virtual Networks, among others.
- · Project was 100% cloud based.
- Developed C# services using the .NET Framework that would communicate with Azure Resources leveraging the use of the Azure SDK.

QA Tester I Wovenware, Inc December 2019 - January 2021

- Led the team's QA efforts during this period, thus establishing a system that future QA Engineers would follow. The team went from having no QA system in place to an established, stable system that would eventually scale once the project grew both in terms of code base as well as team members.
- · Handled all QA related communications with the Project Management Office and other Stakeholders.

LANGUAGES AND TECHNOLOGIES

- Programming Languages: C#, Python, JavaScript. Interested in Golang.
- · Databases: MongoDB (Basic), PostgreSQL (Basic), SQL Server (Basic).
- Operating Systems: Windows, MacOS, Linux (Basic).
- Frameworks and tools: Node.js, .NET, Entity Framework, GraphQL (Basic), Docker & Kubernetes (Basic).
- · Others: Microsoft Azure, Visual Studio, Visual Studio Code, Git, GitHub, Postman, REST APIs, MVC.

EDUCATION

Hato Rey, Puerto Rico

Polytechnic University of Puerto Rico

August 2016 - May 2020

- B.S. in Computer Science. GPA: 3.724 (Graduated Magna Cum Laude).
- Main coursework: Computer Programming in C++, Data Structures, Design and analysis of Algorithms, Computer Architecture, Machine Learning, Database Systems, Operating Systems, Software Engineering.